Children of Witsalnemitea,
大神ウィツァルネミテアの子らよ
オンカミヤムカイのオルヤンクルとして発令します
as High Priest of the Onkamiyamukai,
I hereby proclaim.
わああーっ
I cannot overlook Kunekamun running amok.
クンネカムンの暴走を
見過ごすことはできない
We are going into battle!
出陣する
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
On the Path of Destruction
うわあーっ　わあーっ
What's happening?
これは 一体
は 早う策を
We must hurry with a plan!
Hakuoro...
ハクオロ あくまでクンネカムンに
余に抗うというのか
Are you planning to defy me to the bitter end?
These are our comrades who went before us.
こいつら 先攻してた仲間だ
Here they come!
お出ましだ
Lady Eruruu, please stay behind me.
エルルゥ殿はお下がりください
ウガァ
てやあ
What's with them?
何だ この感じ
They're not even reacting.
こいつら まるで手応えがねえ
So, that's how it is, eh?
そういうことですか
So, this is your answer, Genjimaru?
ゲンジマル それがお前の答えか
It was supposed to have been forbidden
for us to fight each other.
本来 我らが争うのはご法度なのだがな
What's this?
何だと
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
Sister!
お姉ちゃん
Brother!
兄者
Where are we?
ここは？
The outer court area.
開陽殿外延
Inside the castle, huh?
城の中か
So, you've come, Hakuoro.
来てくれたのか ハクオロ
Kuuya-san!
クーヤさん
It's been a while, Eruruu.
I'm glad to see you're well.
久しいな エルルゥ
元気そうで何よりだ
Kuuya-san...
クーヤさん
What is the meaning of turning
everyone against you like this!?
なぜ全てを 敵に回すような真似をした
I am the sovereign of Kunekamun.
余はこのクンネカムンの皇だ
我がシャクコポル族が生き残るために
力を尽くさねばならぬ
I must use all my strength to ensure the
survival of the Shakukopolu race.
That is why.
ただそれだけのこと
Why are you unable to consider coexistence?
なぜ共存を考えない？
I cannot!
できぬ
We cannot coexist with other races.
我らに 他族との共存はできぬ
Even if people are different, we can still live in
harmony, cooperating with each other!
たとえ部族が違っても
助け合って生きていけるはずです
How I have longed for that.
余とて それをどんなに願っていたか
How I have dreamt of joining hands with you.
そなたと手を取り合うことを夢見ていた
So, why then must we be
subjected to such attacks?
なのに なぜ我らがこのような
仕打ちを受けねばならぬ
My people been decimated, burned,
pillaged, raped... killed.
破壊し 火を放ち 略奪し 陵辱し そして殺す
Women and children too, regardless of
whether they begged for their lives.
命乞いする者も 女 子ども関係なく
それでも我らに 共存せよというのか
All were slaughtered.
And you still expect us to coexist!?
The only choices we had were
to control or be controlled!
支配するか されるかでしか
我らの進む道は無い
That is why I set out to unify the land.
だからこそ 余は全土平定に乗り出した
At least, under Kunekamun, people
could coexist regardless of race.
さすれば 我がクンネカムンの下
人は部族の隔たりなく共存できる そう願ってな
That was my wish.
So, is it an unfulfilled wish in the end then?
所詮はかなわぬ夢だったのか
But still, Kuuya-san...
クーヤさん それでも？
くっ　それでも もう後には引けぬのだ
But still, there is no retreat.
やめるんだ
Stop this! I do not want to fight you.
お前とは戦いたくない
I am the sovereign of Kunekamun,
Kuuya Amrulineulka!
余はクンネカムン皇
アムルリネウルカ・クーヤぞ
これが余の皇としてのけじめだ
And this is my resolution as sovereign!
Your Highness...
聖上
があっ
Lord Hakuoro!
ハクオロ殿
ハクオロ そなたとのひととき
楽しかったぞ
Hakuoro, I enjoyed our time together.
It was almost like a dream.
夢のように とても楽しい時であった
It was most enjoyable!
ぐはっ
Hakuoro-san!
ハクオロさん
You must not! You could get pulled into it!
いけませぬ
あなたまで巻き込んでしまっては
I've already been pulled into this.
もう巻き込まれています
私の命は ハクオロさんと
一緒にあるんです
My fate lies with Hakuoro-san!
Could you also have a pact!?
そなたも契約者か
Farewell, Hakuoro!
さらばだ　ハクオロ
うっ ハクオロ殿 脇腹の継ぎ目を
Lord Hakuoro! Aim for the seams
on the side of it!
やあっ
Daddy!
お父さん
Brother!
兄者
Everyone...
皆
うっ はあっ　まだだ　まだ戦える
I... I can still fight...
I cannot allow myself to be defeated.
余は負けるわけにはゆかぬのだ
What's the matter?
Aren't you going to slay me?
どうした　斬らないのか
What!?
何を
If you kill me, you can reverse
the outcome of this war.
私を斬れば 戦況を覆すことができる
Brother!?
兄者
What's wrong?
どうした？　自らの手で敵将の首を
あげる覚悟も無いのか
Can you not take the head of the enemy
general with your own hands?
Do it. Do it!
やれ　やるんだ！
You are a coward.
そなたは卑怯だ 余にできないと知ってて
You know I cannot do that.
I will never mistreat your people.
民のことは 決して悪いようにはしない
だから剣を収めてくれ
So, please put down your sword.
I want you to believe me!
信じてほしい
Is it all right? To really trust you?
よいのだな 本当に信じても
I do not care what happens to me.
余はどうなってもよい
だが 民のことだけは
But my people...
You have my word.
約束する
はっ 余の負けだ
I lose.
You may do as you wish.
そなたの好きなようにするがよい
That was magnificent.
お見事でございます
Your Highness, this place will also soon be...
聖上 ここも間もなく
はあっ　皆 すぐここから離れるんだ
Everyone, you need to get out
of here right away!
What about you, Hakuoro-san?
ハクオロさんは？
It seems the war is not over just yet.
Am I right?
この戦 これで終わりではないようだ
違うか？
Well...
それは…
Are you going to rescind your pact, Evankulgan?
契約を破棄するというのか
エヴェンクルガの男よ
You won't overlook it after all, will you?
やはり 見逃してはくれぬのですな
It's you...
あなた
Dii!?
ディー
It's you...
あなた ディー？
Dii!?
You know him?
知っているのか？
He is an old acquaintance.
He was a philosopher of the Onkamiyamukai.
古い知り合いです
オンカミヤムカイの哲学士
He went missing after setting out on
a journey several years ago.
数年前に旅に出たきり
行方不明になっていたのですが
もう一度問う
汝 我が契約 破棄するつもりか
I will ask you once again.
Do you plan to rescind your pact?
It's about time to put an end to this farce.
そろそろこの茶番
終わりにしたく思いましてな
Oh?
ほーう　だが それがどれほど重い罪か
理解できぬわけではあるまい
But you do understand how serious
a sin that would be, right?
Have you forgotten that I was
already a criminal,
忘れられたか　このゲンジマルが 既に
限りない罪を犯してきた大罪人だということを
who had committed an unspeakable sin?
そして あなたと契約を結んだ訳を
I entered into a pact with you
because of that!
Is that your answer?
それが汝の答えか
Hien! Hauenkua! Where have you
been all this time?
ヒエン ハウエンクア
そなたら 今までどこに
フッフフフフフ
Both of you, capture that intruder!
２人とも そのくせ者を捕らえよ
フッハハハハッ… フフフフ…
What are you doing?
何をしている　余の言っていることが
聞こえないのか
Can't you hear what I'm saying?
申し訳ありませぬが 聞こえませぬ
I beg your pardon, we do not hear you.
What?
何？
Or rather, we are unable to obey your orders.
もはやあなたの命令に
従うことはできませぬ
What? What do you mean?
何？
どういう意味だ
What's so funny?
何がおかしい
Hey, how about I fill you in, you pretty,
little decoration?
ねえねえ 教えてあげようよ
この可愛い可愛い飾り物にさあ
When you realize what a pathetic and
ridiculous existence you have,
自分がどれだけ惨めで 滑稽な存在か知ったら
フフフフ　きっと泣いて喜んでくれるよ
I'm sure you'll shed tears of joy.
ハウエンクア　そなた
Hauenkua... How dare you?
黙れ！
Silence!
Both of you, open your eyes!
２人とも目を覚ませ
それに取り込まれてはならん
Do not get yourselves involved with him!
Hien, don't you realize what you are doing?
ヒエンよ おのれが今
何をしているのか 気付かぬのか
Elder, I believe I am sane and fully
comprehend what I am doing.
タウロ 某は正気であり 何をしているのか
理解しているつもりです
I have determined this course
to be my true calling!
その上で おのれの進むべき
真の道と決めた
Even at the expense of betraying
all that you had believed in?
貴様を信じていた
全ての者を裏切ってまでもか
And what about you, Elder?
How can you act this way?
タウロこそ なぜこのような真似をなさる
A pact with the Master is absolute.
You should know that better than any.
主への契約は絶対　それはあなたが
一番よく知っているはず
なればこそ問うのだ
人ごとき身でそれに関われば
That is why I question you.
If you involve yourself with him,
only unbearable sin and destruction
will lie ahead for you!
その先に待つのは耐え難き罪と 破滅ぞ
Destruction?
破滅？
What are you saying?
何を言っておる　ゲンジマル
これはどういうことなのだ
Genjimaru, what is this about?
It is not for you to know.
汝が知るべきことではない
What!?
Sovereign of Kunekamun,
クンネカムンの皇よ
汝 与えられしきを無にするか
are you going to waste the devices
that I bestowed upon you?
What are you talking about?
何を言って…
Eruruu, get out of here!
Take Kuuya and run!
エルルゥ 行け
クーヤを連れてここを出るんだ
えっ はい
Y... Yes!
Oh, no you don't, you resilient
little cockroaches!
そうはいかないんだよ 死に損ないども！
Kuuya-san!
クーヤさん
At this rate...
このままでは
What am I? What was I?
私は一体 何を
Hakuoro-sama...
ハクオロ様
I will teleport everybody, so don't worry,
you can release your powers.
皆を転移させます
ですから 構わずお力の解放を
How much do you know?
ウルトリィ 何を知っている？
Here we go!
行きます
ああ 何？
What?
This place is...
ここって
Teleportation!?
転移術？
It seems there was a high ranking
magician among you,
高位の術者がいたようだけど
お前らだけ残ってどうするつもりなんだい
but what do you plan to accomplish
by staying behind?
ゲンジマル なぜ行かなかった
Genjimaru! Why didn't you go?
I still have unfinished business here.
某には まだやることがありましてな
ハハハッ　何 訳分からんことを
What are you talking about!?
ぬあー
うわっ うっ うはあっ はあっ
What is that?
何だ？
It couldn't be! It's you?
まさか お前が
ひひっ 来るな 来るな
Stay away! Stay away!
I shall be your opponent!
某が相手をする
No!
邪魔だ
You monster!
化け物
Hien, can't you see!?
ヒエン お前には見えぬのか
I can see... I surpass you!
見えている　某は あなたを超える
どああー
ぎゃあ
がはっ
Hien!
ヒエン
Do it, Hauenkua.
やれ ハウエンクア
ひい
Do it!
やれ
ひいいっ
ハハハ ハハハ…　体が軽い
力が溢れて来るよ　最高の気分だよ
My body feels so light.
It's overflowing with power!
What a terrific feeling!
フフフフハ ハハハハ ヒハハ
ギャハハハハー！
Please, stop it already!
もうおやめくだされ
I only freed his heart.
This is the result of his desires.
心を解き放ってやっただけだ
あれこそが あの男の望んだ結果だ
Hauenkua!
ハウエンクア
ううっ 来るな
だあー！
Stay back! I have no reason to kill you!
来るな　お前を殺す理由は無い
This is nothing.
これしき　うっ はあっ
某の名はヒエン
ゲンジマルの血を引く武士（もののふ）
My name is Hien, a warrior
descendant of Genjimaru...
The fool!
馬鹿者が
くはっ はあっ はあっ
So, this is what I am after all...
やはり 私は
Hakuoro? That is the name you go by now?
ハクオロ　今は
そう名乗っているのだったな
It would certainly be fascinating
to fight you, however,
確かに我らが戦うのは この上なき魅惑
だが 直に戦うべきではないことを
汝も承知しているはずだ
you should also know that we cannot
engage in combat with each other.
But then you would have no one worth fighting.
だが しかし そうなると
汝の相手をできる駒が無いか
Ah, yes, since you have chosen that girl,
そうだな
汝があの娘を選んだのなら
こちらも目覚めさせる頃合いか
I guess it is time for me to
awaken my other side.
Camus!
カミュ
Mister...
おじ様？
You were watching?
見ていたのか
I didn't mean to.
そんなつもりじゃ
Dii! I was worried about you.
ディー 私 あなたのことが心配で
And then...
そしたら
No!
いかん
Come, Mutsumi.
ムツミよ
来い
No, don't come out!
嫌
出て来ないで
Did you call, Father?
お呼びですか
お父様
I leave this to you.
任せる
はい
Yes!
Camus, stop it!
カミュ
よせ
Now then, Genjimaru, answer me.
さて ゲンジマル　答えてもらおう
Are you going to waste the devices
that I bestowed upon you?
汝 我がクンネカムンに
与えた機を無にするか
Their power is too much for the young
sovereign of Kunekamun.
幼いクンネカムン皇には 身に余る力
That is the reason I have come here.
故に汝がおり
こうして私が来たのではないか
So you will not withdraw?
どうしても 引いてはくださらぬか
I'm afraid not. You should be
well aware of that.
残念だが それは汝も
承知しているはずだが
The price of the Avu Kamu was to enter
into a pact to be my people.
アブ・カムゥを与える代償として
我が眷属となる契約
Have you forgotten that you
stood witness to this?
汝もその場に立ち会ったことを忘れたか
But that was a pact with the previous sovereign.
それは先皇との契約
It has nothing to do with Kuuya-sama.
クーヤ様には関係ありませぬ
No matter how many years pass,
I cannot alter the agreement.
たとえ幾年の時が流れようと
契約は変えられない
You can't alter it, no matter what?
どうしても でありますか
Enough.
くどい
Those days when I single-mindedly served you
ただがむしゃらに あなた様に挑んだ日々
were such nostalgic, happy days that
filled my heart with great joy.
懐かしく心踊るまでに
楽しき日々でありました
Even as I turn my sword against you now,
あの日 あの時 牙を抜かれども
絶対たるあなた様にお仕えした日々は
I still say that those days spent
serving you were my happiest.
何よりの喜びでありました
Stop it.
やめよ
There is no need to try so
hard anymore, so please...
もう無理をする必要はありませぬ
どうか 後はただ １人の女としての
幸せをおつかみくだされ
When this is over, try to find
happiness as just a woman.
You fool!
たわけが　汝に打ち込まれた楔
我に牙を向いた時にどうなるか 忘れたか
Don't you recall what happens to those who
lead me into a pact and then turn against me?
Stop this, I do not wish to lose a friend.
やめよ　友を失いたくはない
某を まだ友と呼んでくださいますか
You still call me your friend?
Genjimaru...
ゲンジマル…？
ハクオロ殿！
Lord Hakuoro!
I leave... I leave the rest to you!
後を 後を頼みまするぞ！
Genjimaru...
ゲンジマ…
Magnificent! A mere mortal
attempting to injure me!
見事だ　人の身で我に傷を負わせようとは
Let's go. I have no further business here.
行くぞ　もうここには用は無い
Are you sure?
いいの？
It doesn't concern me.
構わん
ああ ゲンジ… ああ… はあっ…
Genji... ma...
Ordinarily, you would have been
under a pact to serve me.
本来ならば 汝は我が眷属となるべき
契約がなされていた
However, that has been
rescinded by his wishes.
だが それはたっての願いにより
破棄された
Your life has been redeemed by Genjimaru.
Don't let it go to waste.
ゲンジマルに救われたその身
粗末にしないことだ
We shall leave this place
この場は引こう
ゲンジマルの命を代償としてな
as compensation for Genjimaru's sacrifice.
I don't forgive those who go against Father.
お父様に仇なす人 許さない
But I will not harm you, for that
is what this man wished.
でも あなたには何もしない
あの男がそれを望んだから
Instead, you will lose something
precious to you.
その代わり あなたは大切なものを失う
うぐっ
Those Kunekamun dogs!
What a terrible thing to do!
クンネカムンの奴ら こんなひでえことを
No, those are the Flames of Purification.
いいえ これは浄化の炎
何だ そりゃあ
What's that?
Camus...
カミュ
Hakuoro-san...
ハクオロさん
Chaos moves and shapes the world.
混乱が世を動かし 世界を形づくる
We must continue this endless fight.
我らは終わらない戦いを
続けなければならないのだ
Right, my other half?
なあ 我が半身よ
Why couldn't you have chosen me?
どうして私を選んでくれなかったの
Farewell, my other father.
もう１人のお父様
ああ ああ　わああ
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
魂から結びつき 私を恋い温めて
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
守られてまどろむ宵
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
Traces of an Ancient Dream